Guide to the National Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
National Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association records
1903-1955
1918-1947
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0512
0512-001
National Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association (U.S.)
11.54 cubic feet (13 boxes)
Correspondence, minutes, journals, legislative materials, financial records, ephemera, agreements, reports, constitutions and bylaws of the union on national and local levels of a labor organization in Seattle
A National Maritime Labor organization. Throughout the 1920s, MEBA experienced a sharp decline in its membership. From about 22,000 in 1920 to 5,000 in 1934. In spite of this, during the period between World War I and World War II it was successful in raising wages, lowering working hours, and establishing the union hiring hall.
Correspondence, minutes, journals, legislative materials, financial records, ephemera, agreements, reports, constitutions and bylaws of the union on national and local levels. The correspondence is mainly that of William Peel, business manager of Local, 38 and so primarily reflects the activities of MEBA's Seattle branch.
Open to all users.
Some records stored offsite; advanced notice required for use.
Purchased from Shorey's Book Store, 1/5/1965.
The Greenwood Encyclopedia of American Institutions: Labor Unions
National Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association (U.S.)$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); American Federation of Labor.$bCommittee for Industrial Organization; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Inland Boatmen's Union of the Pacific; Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Ships and Shipping; Washington (State); Seattle
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1920-1947; SERIES I (Box-folder 1-4)
  - General (Alphabetically Organized), 1920-1947; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/1-2/41, 4/12-4/71)
    - Ab-Ad, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Al, 1929-1936 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Alaska, 1934-1943 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - American Mail Line, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Am, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - An, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Ar-At, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Ba, 1929-1939 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Bec-Ber, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Becker, Henry, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Bel-Ben, 1929-1939 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Bj-Bl, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Bo, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Bu-By, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Br, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Ca, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Cha-Chi, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Chr-Cl, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - CIO, National, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - CIO, Seattle Industrial Labor Council, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - CIO, Washington State Industrial Council, 1938 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Cob-Com, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Con-Cor, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Cou-Cox, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Cr, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Cu, 1929-1938 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Da-Di, 1921, 1934-1941 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Do-Du, 1933-1940 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Ea-Ei, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Em-Ev, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Fa-Fen, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Fer, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Fl, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Fi-Fu, 1921-1942 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - French, C.R., 1936-1940 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Ga-Go, 1929-1942 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Gr-Gu, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Ha, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - He-Hi, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Ho, 1921-1942 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Hu, 1930-1936 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - International Longshoremens' Association, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 1/42)
    - In, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Ir-Iv, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/44)
    - Ja, 1932-1940 (Box-folder 1/45)
    - Je-Jo, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 1/46)
    - K, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 1/47)
    - La, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 1/48)
    - Le, 1921-1942 (Box-folder 1/49)
    - Li, 1931-1942 (Box-folder 1/50)
    - Lo, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 1/51)
    - Lu-Ly, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 1/52)
    - Ma, 1936-1944 (Box-folder 1/53)
    - Mac, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 1/54)
    - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 1/55-58)
    - MEBA National, 1931, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 2/1-41)
    - Me, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Merriweather, R., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 4/13-18)
    - Mi, 1920, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Miller, Dave W., 1921-1931 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Mo-Mu, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - National Association of Marine Engineers of Canada No. 7, 1935-1938, 1942 (Box-folder 4/22-4/26)
    - National Organization of Masters' Mates and Pilots of America, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Na-Ne, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 4/28)
    - No-Ny, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 4/29)
    - O-Ol, 1923-1940 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - Or-Oy, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Pacific Coast Labor Bureau, 1924-1939 (Box-folder 4/32-33)
    - Pac-Pal, 1930-1941 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - Par-Pay, 1932-1939 (Box-folder 4/35)
    - Parker, Howell (Captain), 1932-1935 (Box-folder 4/36-37)
    - Pe, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 4/38)
    - Pflug, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 4/39)
    - Ph-Pl, 1931-1939 (Box-folder 4/40)
    - Pr, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 4/41)
    - Pu, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 4/42)
    - Q, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 4/43)
    - R, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 4/44)
    - Sa-Sc, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 4/45)
    - Se, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 4/46)
    - Sh-Sj, 1932-1939 (Box-folder 4/47)
    - Sl-So, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 4/48)
    - St, 1921, 1929-1938 (Box-folder 4/49)
    - Su-Sw, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/50)
    - T, 1929-1944 (Box-folder 4/51)
    - U, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 4/52)
    - U.S. (Misc.), 1934-1943 (Box-folder 4/53)
    - U.S. Coast Guard, 1947 (Box-folder 4/54)
    - U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1941 (Box-folder 4/55)
    - U.S. Congress-Misc., 1937-1938 (Box-folder 4/56)
    - U.S. Congress-Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 4/57)
    - U.S. Congress-Magnuson, Warren G., 1936-1938 (Box-folder 4/58)
    - U.S. Congress-Wallgren, Mon C., 1934-1938 (Box-folder 4/59)
    - U.S. Senate-Bone, Homer T., 1937-1938 (Box-folder 4/60)
    - U.S. Senate Schwellenbach, Lewis B., 1937-1938 (Box-folder 4/61)
    - Va, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 4/62)
    - Vo, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 4/63)
    - Washington, 1929-1942 (Box-folder 4/64)
    - Washington Shipowner's Association, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 4/65)
    - Wa, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 4/66)
    - Washington (State), 1933-1942 (Box-folder 4/67)
    - We, 1921, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 4/68)
    - Wh-Wi, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 4/69)
    - Wo-Wy, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 4/70)
    - X-Y-Z, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 4/71)
  - MEBA Locals, 1920-1946; Subseries B (Box-folder 2/42-3/57, 4/1-4/11)
    - Local 1 - Buffalo, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 2/42)
    - Local 2 - Cleveland, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 2/43)
    - Local 5 - Baltimore, 1936-1939, 1941 (Box-folder 2/44)
    - Local 6 - Victoria, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 2/45)
    - Local 11 - Norfolk, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 2/46)
    - Local 12 - New Orleans, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 2/47)
    - Local 13 - Philadelphia, 1934-1942 (Box-folder 2/48)
    - Local 24 - Paducah, 1937 (Box-folder 2/49)
    - Local 30 - Pittsburg, 1941 (Box-folder 2/50)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/51)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/52)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/53)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/54)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/55)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/56)
    - Local 33 - New York City, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 2/57)
    - Local 38 - Seattle, 1920-1944 (Box-folder 2/58)
    - Local 38 - Seattle, 1920-1944 (Box-folder 2/59)
    - Local 38 - Seattle, 1920-1944 (Box-folder 2/60)
    - Local 38 - Seattle, 1920-1944 (Box-folder 2/61)
    - Local 38 - Seattle, 1920-1944 (Box-folder 2/62)
    - Local 40 - Galveston, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Local 40 - Galveston, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Local 41 - Portland, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Local 49, 1930 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Local 59 - Boston, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Local 77 - Manitowoc, Wisconsin, 1941 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Local 79 - San Pedro, California, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Local 80, 1921 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Local 96 - Gamboa, Panama, 1937 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/38)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/39)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/40)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/41)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/42)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/43)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/44)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/45)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/46)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/47)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/48)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/49)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/50)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/51)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/52)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/53)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/54)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/55)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/56)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3/57)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Local 97 - San Francisco, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Local 99 - Houston, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 4/11)
- JOURNALS AND NOTEBOOKS, 1903-1946; SERIES II (Box-folder 5-7)
  - Assorted Journals and Notebooks, 1920-1944; Subseries A (Box-folder 5)
    - Attendance Record, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Crew Records - Engineers, 1940 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Libel Suit Appeal-Blake, Secretary National Ass. vs. Trainer, Secretary Local #33-Joint Appendix, 1944 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Libel Suit Appeal-Blake, Secretary National Ass. vs. Trainer, Secretary Local #33-Brief for Appellant, 1944 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Marine Engineers Blue Book Local #38, 1903 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Marine Engineers Blue Book Local #38, 1903 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Membership Records, Local #38, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Picket Book (Strike Picketing), 1936 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Picket Book (Strike Picketing)-Loose Materials, 1936 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Trustees Records (Minutes), 1920-1942 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Unemployed Register and Picket Book, 1938 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Hall Rules, n.d. (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Financial Records, 1914-1946; Subseries B (Box-folder 6-7)
    - Financial Records, 1914-circa 1921 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Financial Records, 1917-1936 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Financial Records-Rents, 1927-1946 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Financial Records-Disbursement. Monthly Distribution of Expenses, 1922-1939 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Financial Records-Receipts and Disbursements, 1923-1936 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Financial Records-Daily Cash Book, 1930-1936 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Financial Records-Daily Cash Books, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 7/4)
- MINUTES, 1925-1943; SERIES III (Box-folder 8)
  - Minutes of Joint Negotiating Committee of Allied Unions, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Licensed Personnel Board, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Labor Unions Relief Council, 1938 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - MEBA Conferences-Atlantic and Gulf Coasts, 1936-1939, 1941 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - MEBA Conferences-Atlantic and Gulf Coasts, 1936-1939, 1941 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - MEBA Conferences-Pacific Coast, 1935-1937, 1941 (Box-folder 8/6-10)
  - MEBA Conferences-Pacific Coast, 1935-1937, 1941 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - MEBA Conferences-Pacific Coast, 1935-1937, 1941 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - MEBA Conferences-Pacific Coast, 1935-1937, 1941 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - MEBA Conferences-Pacific Coast, 1935-1937, 1941 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - MEBA Conference-Atlantic and Gulf Coasts-Business Managers' Conference, 1936 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1935 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Minutes and Ephemera, 1936 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Minutes and Cash Disbursements for Voice of the Federation, 1937 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Minutes and Ephemera, 1937 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Portland, 1937 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - 3rd Annual Convention, 1937 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Minutes and Resolutions, 1938 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast Council #1 (Washington District Council, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast Council #1 (Washington District Council, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast Council #1 (Washington District Council, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast Council #1 (Washington District Council, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 8/22)
  - National Convention - MEBA, 1936 (Box-folder 8/23)
  - National Maritime Labor Council, 1936 (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Seattle Industrial Labor Union Council, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 8/25-26)
  - Steamship Owners Association of the Pacific Coast- Conference, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8/27)
  - MEBA - National Executive Committee, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 8/28)
  - MEBA - Joint Strike Committee, 1936 (Box-folder 8/29)
  - Legislation Relating to Maritime Affairs - H.R. 6243, 1925 (Box-folder 8/30)
  - Legislation Relating to Maritime Affairs - H.R. 6243, 1935 (Box-folder 8/31)
  - Legislation Relating to Maritime Affairs - Marine Act of 1936 (Box-folder 8/32)
  - Legislation Relating to Maritime Affairs - Marine Act of 1936, 1935-1939, 1941 (Box-folder 8/33)
  - Legislation Relating to Maritime Affairs - Marine Act of 1936, 1943 (Box-folder 8/34)
  - Gulf Assessment Tax, on Unions, 1937 (Box-folder 8/35)
  - Assorted Minutes, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 8/36)
- CONVENTIONS and MEETINGS, 1926-1947; SERIES IV (Box-folder 9/1-15)
  - Commemoration Ceremony for the 150th Anniversary of the First Congress of U.S. under the Constitution, 1939; Subseries A (Box-folder 9/1)
  - National MEBA Conventions, 1926, 1944, 1947; Subseries B (Box-folder 9/2-9/14)
    - 51st, 68th, National MEBA Conventions, 1926, 1944 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - 69th Annual MEBA Convention-Proceedings, 1945 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - 71st Annual NMEBA Convention Proceedings, 1947 (Box-folder 9/14)
  - National MEBA Meeting of Business Managers and Delegates of Subordinate Associations, 1946; Subseries C (Box-folder 9/15)
- NATIONAL INDUSTRIAL RECOVERY ADMINISTRATION-HEARNING ON CODES OF FAIR PRACTICES AND COMPETITION, THE SHIPPING INDUSTRY, 1933; SERIES V (Box-folder 9/16)
- PAMPHLETS, 1926-1946; SERIES VI (Box-folder 9/17-9/21)
  - National MEBA Dispatches, 1935 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - National MEBA Dispatches, 1936 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - National MEBA Dispatches, 1937 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - National Recovery Administration Codes of Fair Competition, National MEBA Dispatches, Pacific American Shipowners’ Association, National MEBA Conventions, 1933-1947 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Assorted Pamphlets, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 9/21)
- INTEROFFICE MATERIAL, SUBJECT FILES, 1933-1946; SERIES VII (Box-folder 9/22-9/33)
  - Charges Against Members, 1935 (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Ferry Ballot, 1941 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - Inland Boatmen's Union Ballot, 1941 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Life Boat Information, n.d. (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Lists - Miscellaneous 1933,1946 (Box-folder 9/26)
  - McGrady's Speech, 1935 (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Nominations, 1938 (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Nominations, 1940 (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Petitions, 1935 (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Point Ancha Data, 1935 (Box-folder 9/31)
  - Selected Service Data - Draft Deferment, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 9/32)
  - Wreck Benefits, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 9/33)
- ARBITRATION, 1935-1946; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 10/1-10/3, 10/6-10/8, 10/10-10/11, 10/13-10/15, 10/18-10/21, 10/23, 10/25, 10/45)
  - Pacific American Ship owners of the Pacific Coast-Negotiations, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Pacific American Ship owners of the Pacific Coast-Negotiations, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 10/17)
  - MEBA and McCormick Steamship Co. et al, 1935 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - MEBA and McCormick Steamship Co. et al, 1935 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Dollar Steamship Lines, Matson Navigation Co. et al, 1937 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Proceedings Before James Lawrence Fly, Arbitrator (Union Exhibits), 1946 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Proceedings Before James Lawrence Fly, Arbitrator (Union Exhibits), 1946 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Proceedings Before James Lawrence Fly, Arbitrator (Union Exhibits), 1946 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Proceedings Before James Lawrence Fly, Arbitrator (Union Exhibits), 1946 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Pacific American Shipowners' Association, 1938 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Fitzpatrick vs. Alaskan Packers, 1939 (Box-folder 10/14)
  - Assorted Arbitrations, 1935 (Box-folder 10/15)
  - IBU/MEBA Controversy, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 10/18)
  - Charges Preferred, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 10/19)
  - State Inspection-Supreme Court and Ruling, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 10/20)
  - Assorted, 1937 (Box-folder 10/21)
  - Swayne and Hoyt, NLRB Decision, 1938 (Box-folder 10/23)
  - Steam Schooner Controversy, 1936, 1940 (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Awards by Geo. Marlin Board, circa 1935 (Box-folder 10/45)
- STRIKE CORRESPONDENCE, 1934-1938; SERIES IX (Box-folder 10/22, 10/24, 10/43, 10/47)
  - Swayn and Hoyt Controversy, 1938 (Box-folder 10/22)
  - Tow Boat Strike, 1935 (Box-folder 10/24)
  - Fink List, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 10/43)
  - Tanker Strike, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 10/47)
- AGREEMENTS, 1932-1955; SERIES X (Box-folder 10/4-10/5, 10/9, 10/16, 10/26-10/39, 10/40-10/42, 10/44 11/1-11/9, 11/35)
  - Alaska Steamship Company and Metal Trades Council, 1939 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - American Communications Association, CIO, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Seamen's Wage Exhibit, 1946 (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Canadian Wage, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 10/16)
  - International Packing Co., 1935 (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Assorted, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 10/27)
  - East Coast Tow Boat Agreement, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 10/28)
  - Union Sulphur Co., Alaska Steamship Co., 1935 (Box-folder 10/29)
  - Assorted, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/30)
  - American Pacific Whaling Company, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 10/31)
  - Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, 1937 (Box-folder 10/32)
  - Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, circa 1932-circa 1939 (Box-folder 10/39)
  - Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, circa. 1934-1937 (Box-folder 11/44)
  - Hiring Systems-Proposed, 1936 (Box-folder 10/33)
  - Dispatching Systems - Proposed, 1938 (Box-folder 10/34)
  - Alaska Operators - Proposed, 1937 (Box-folder 10/35)
  - Assorted, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 10/36)
  - Assorted, 1939 (Box-folder 10/37)
  - Steamship Owners' Association of the Pacific Coast (offshore steam schooners), 1935 (Box-folder 10/38)
  - Steamship Owners' Association of the Pacific Coast (offshore steam schooners), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/42)
  - Steamship Owners' Association of the Pacific Coast, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/44)
  - Alaska Company Operations, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 10/41)
  - Proposed Medical System, 1939 (Box-folder 10/46)
  - Proposed, 1933-circa 1937 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Proposed, 1934- 1937 (Box-folder 10/40)
  - Assorted, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Washington Shipowners Tenetive Agreement, 1939 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - (Booklets), 1944-1955 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Assorted, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Assorted, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Proposed, 1934- 1935 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Assorted, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - Firemen, Oilers, Watertenders and Wipers and Sailors, 1940 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Tow Boat, circa 1935 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Washington Shipowners' Association, 1941 (Box-folder 11/35)
- REPORTS, 1919-1943; SERIES XI (Box-folder 11/10-11/26, 11/28, 11/31)
  - Mr. Geo M. Corwin. Copy of the President's Report, 1943 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Relief Fund-Members if Debt, 1928 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - Audits, 1922-1934, 1943 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Audits, 1922-1934, 1943 (Box-folder 11/25)
  - Audits, 1922-1934, 1943 (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Financial Secretary, Treasurer, 1921-1943 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Financial Secretary, Treasurer, 1921-1943 (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Financial Secretary, Treasurer, 1921-1943 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Trustees etc., 1931-1937 (Box-folder 11/17)
  - 30th MEBA Pacific Coast Conference (July 1938) (Box-folder 11/18)
  - McGrady Conference (August 6, 1935), 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Investigation-Working Conditions, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - San Francisco Bay Area District Council #2, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - Wage Scale, 1937 (Box-folder 11/22)